Class of 1881 Records, 1876-1961, 1979, 1998
Smith College Archives
Class of 1881 Records
1876-1961, 1979, 1998
Smith College. Class of 1881.
RG 80 UUID:6c2cc789-297b-43fb-be02-dad9064e0484
5 boxes (2 linear feet)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains black and white photographs, class letters, publications, correspondence, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, photo albums, and student's class notes, as well as information regarding the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1881.
The Class of 1881 was the third graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1881 Records contain materials describing the history of the Class of 1881. Types of materials include black and white photographs, class letters, publications, correspondence, newspaper clippings, scrapbooks, photo albums, and student's class notes, as well as information regarding the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1881.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1881 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Box missing since Feb. 1999 (Box 1386)
- Class of 1881: Class Letters 1883, 1893, 1895-97, 1899, 1900, 1902, 1914-16, 1939-41, 1945-46 (Box 1387, Folder 1)
- Class of 1881: Clippings undated (Box 1387, Folder 2)
- Class of 1881: Commencement 1881 (Box 1387, Folder 3)
- Class of 1881: Commencement Music 1881 (Box 1387, Folder 4)
- Class of 1881: Germans 1880-81 (Box 1387, Folder 5)
- Class of 1881: Group Photos 1881 (Box 1387, Folder 6)
- Class of 1881: Official Circular 1881 (Box 1387, Folder 7)
- Class of 1881: Organization 1880-81, 1887 (Box 1387, Folder 8)
- Class of 1881: Publications 1888-89, 1891, 1894-95, 1897, 1899, 1904-05 (Box 1387, Folder 9)
- Class of 1881: Reunions 1887, 1889, 1915-16, 1937, 1941, 1945-46 (Box 1387, Folder 10)
- Class of 1881: Reunion Photographs 1931, 1941 (Box 1387, Folder 11)
- Class of 1881: Arms, Harriet Elizabeth (Box 1388, Folder 1)
- Class of 1881: Barnard, Mary A. 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 2)
- Class of 1881: Browne, Sarah Alice 1881, 1887, 1906, 1912-15, 1928, 1979 (Box 1388, Folder 3)
- Class of 1881: Bryant, Martha 1881, 1918-19 (Box 1388, Folder 4)
- Class of 1881: Cartwright, Annie 1919 (Box 1388, Folder 5)
- Class of 1881: Cheever, Charlotte Barrell (Box 1388, Folder 6)
- Class of 1881: Clapp, Lucia Maria 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 7)
- Class of 1881: Clarke, Rachel 1881, 1934 (Box 1388, Folder 8)
- Class of 1881: Cunningham, Marion Hobart 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 9)
- Class of 1881: Dibble, Mary 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 10)
- Class of 1881: Dunton, Harriette Mandana 1881, 1918-19 (Box 1388, Folder 11)
- Class of 1881: Dunton, Harriette Mandana (Class notes, Religion and Literature) undated (Box 1388, Folder 12)
- Class of 1881: Dunton, Harriette Mandana (Notebook "Essays") undated (Box 1388, Folder 13)
- Class of 1881: Ensign, Mary Louise 1881, 1905 (Box 1388, Folder 14)
- Class of 1881: Fosdick, Lucy 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 15)
- Class of 1881: Fosdick, Sarah 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 16)
- Class of 1881: Gill, Laura Drake 1881, 1888, 1902, 1909, 1913, 1918, 1925 (Box 1388, Folder 17)
- Class of 1881: Gill, Laura Drake (The Cosmopolitan, "Women as College Presidents") 1902 (Box 1388, Folder 18)
- Class of 1881: Gray, Emma C.B. 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 19)
- Class of 1881: Guyer, Caroline 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 20)
- Class of 1881: Haven, Laura Belle 1879-81, 1883, 1920, 1961 (Box 1388, Folder 21)
- Class of 1881: Heard, Sarah 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 22)
- Class of 1881: Hoyt, Anna Marilla 1883-84, 1914-15 (Box 1388, Folder 23)
- Class of 1881: Hoyt, Anna Marilla (Photographs) 1881 (Box 1388, Folder 24)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Box 1388, Folder 25)
- Class of 1881: Joel, Julia M. 1881, 1920, 1936, 1981 (Box 1388, Folder 26)
- Class of 1881: Kellogg, Sarah Delano (General) 1881 (Box 1389, Folder 1)
- Class of 1881: Kellogg, Sarah Delano (Letters) 1920, 1923, 1929-31, 1934-35, 1938-41 (Box 1389, Folder 2)
- Class of 1881: King, Effie 1881 (Box 1389, Folder 3)
- Class of 1881: Lathe, Agnes 1881 (Box 1389, Folder 4)
- Class of 1881: Leonard, Mary Adeline undated (Box 1389, Folder 5)
- Class of 1881: Lewis, Frances 1881, 1888 (Box 1389, Folder 6)
- Class of 1881: Miner, Affa S. (Lecture Notes) 1878-81 (Box 1389, Folder 7)
- Class of 1881: Miner, Affa S. (Letters) 1876-77, 1879, 1881, 1919-20, 1931 (Box 1389, Folder 8)
- Class of 1881: Miner, Affa S. (Photographs) 1881, 1893 (Box 1389, Folder 9)
- Class of 1881: Nettleton, Mary Eliza 1956 (Box 1389, Folder 10)
- Class of 1881: Owen, Amelia 1881 (Box 1389, Folder 11)
- Class of 1881: Pearson, Helen 1881 (Box 1389, Folder 12)
- Class of 1881: Pratt, Harriet 1881, 1883, 1890 (Box 1389, Folder 13)
- Class of 1881: Proctor, Mary 1880-81, 1905, 1918, 1928, 1930 (Box 1389, Folder 14)
- Class of 1881: Saunderson, Laura Maria (Correspondence re: M.A.) 1885 (Box 1389, Folder 15)
- Class of 1881: Saunderson, Laura Maria (Photographs) 1881, 1888 (Box 1389, Folder 16)
- Class of 1881: Seymour, Clara 1881 (Box 1389, Folder 17)
- Class of 1881: Taylor, Isabelle (Correspondence) 1916, 1931 (Box 1389, Folder 18)
- Class of 1881: Taylor, Isabelle (Photographs) 1881 (Box 1389, Folder 19)
- Class of 1881: Tyler, Mary E. 1917, 1919, 1931 (Box 1389, Folder 20)
- Class of 1881: Warner, Harriet Blanche undated (Box 1389, Folder 21)
- Class of 1881: Willmer, Amy 1881, 1883, 1919, 1931 (Box 1389, Folder 22)
- Class of 1881: Mary Frances Dibble Smith (Album) undated (Box 1390)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Correspondence) 1899, 1900, 1906, 1916, 1931, 1933, 1938, 1941, 1945 (Box 1391, Folder 1)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Material on her Old Age) 1923, 1929, 1933-34, 1954, 1956-57, 1959, 1998 (Box 1391, Folder 2)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Photographs) 1881, 1909, 1940, 1952, 1956-57 (Box 1391, Folder 3)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Round Robin) 1917-18, 1920, 1922-23, 1926, 1930-45 (Box 1391, Folder 4)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Secretary of Class Papers) 1915-28, 1936-38 (Box 1391, Folder 5)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Scrapbook / Photo Album) 1881-1936 (Box 1391, Folder 6)
- Class of 1881: Huntington, Eliza Prentiss (Scrapbook) 1878-82 (Box 1391)